Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today
we're talking about going out for a drink.
That's right.
We're going to a bar and
we're going to order cocktails.
So we're going to learn
all about the different
types of cocktails and a little bit
more language that you can use at a bar.
Exactly.
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
We'll be back in a moment.
What can I get you?
I live a cosmo, please.
Dude, you can't order a cosmo.
That's a lady's drink.
You're embarrassing me.
What are you talking about?
It's a good drink.
It's too soft.
Order something with
a little more kick to it.
Fine.
I'll have a sex on the beach.
You have got to be kidding me.
Come on.
It's delicious.
Especially when served with
a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it.
I'm ordering for you.
I'll have a scotch on the rocks and
my friend here will have a Manhattan.
Put it on my tab.
Here.
This is a real drink.
Strong.
This is going to get me wasted.
That's the idea.
All right.
We're back.
So now let's take a look at some of
those drinks on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So in language takeaway today, we're
going to focus on the names of drinks.
So we heard four of
them in today's dialogue.
What was that first one, Marco?
The first one was a cosmo
or also called a cosmopolitan.
OK, so this is something
if you watch the
TV show Sex in the
City, you will have heard
before because the
girls always order cosmos.
Now, a cosmopolitan is
served in a martini glass, right?
Right.
You've seen the martini glass.
It kind of looks like a triangle.
And it's very easy to spill.
Yeah.
That's right.
So what does a cosmo have?
Because obviously a
cocktail is a combination of
different liquors or alcohol with
maybe juices and stuff like that.
So what does a cosmo have?
That's a good question.
Cosmo is a vodka drink, I believe,
and it's served in a martini glass.
But it's generally considered
a drink for ladies, for women.
Why is that?
Probably because it's a weaker
drink, but also because it's
popular in the media and in
movies and stuff as a women's drinks.
So that's how I got that.
I see.
All right.
Very good.
So that's what a cosmo is.
If we move on to
another very popular drink,
a little bit more
tropical, I think everyone
always has it when
the Caribbean or when
they're on vacation at the beach,
it's called a sex on the beach.
Okay.
This name might make
you laugh because sex
on the beach, it's very descriptive,
but it's actually a very common drink.
Right.
And in the dialogue,
he talks about how he
likes to have this drink served
in a pineapple or a coconut.
So that means it's very fruity.
And I think it's a rum drink, right?
Yeah.
And it usually has
either a coconut juice in
it or maybe some
pineapple juice, very fruity.
I think even they, I
think they add a little
bit of vanilla or even ice cream
or milk or something like that.
So it's very fruity.
It's kind of like a milkshake with liquor.
Weird.
Yeah.
I don't know that I've ever had one, but
this is the part of the dialogue where his
friend says, come on, you need to
buy something that's more manly.
He orders a scotch on the rocks instead.
Okay.
So a scotch is a type of liquor.
It's a whiskey.
That's right.
Scotch whiskey comes from
Scotland and it's a whiskey drink and
basically scotch on the rocks
means scotch poured over ice ice.
So in this case, rocks means
ice and you'll hear this often.
Do you want that on the rocks?
Do you want that on ice?
Right.
So you don't say I want whiskey with ice
or you don't say I want scotch with ice.
You can just say on the rocks.
Scotch on the rocks.
So it may be if you're ordering
a rum drink and you don't
want it mixed with anything,
you can say, rum on the rocks.
On the rocks.
Very good.
And not only are we
ordering a scotch on the
rocks, but we're also
ordering a Manhattan.
So what does a Manhattan have?
All right.
A Manhattan is a very strong cocktail.
It has bourbon, which is a kind
of whiskey, an American whiskey.
It has vermouth, which is also very
strong ingredient, and it has bitters.
What is bitters?
Bidders is another
kind of ingredient that is
often used in cocktails
to make things bitter.
Ah, okay.
So it's not a sweet drink.
No, no, no.
It's not a sweet drink.
Although they
sometimes put a little bit of
lemon or orange rind in
the drink and that's the skin.
A little orange.
Okay.
So both these drinks are pretty strong.
They're very interesting though.
All the ones that we've seen, the Cos,
Mo, the Sex, and the Beach, they're all
called cocktails and
the cocktail has the
characteristic that it
usually has alcohol, right?
That's right.
So cocktail is a mix of different
ingredients, but it's an alcohol-based drink.
Okay.
You can also get non-alcoholic
cocktails, so there is that option.
All right.
Very good.
So when we take a
break, let's listen to the
dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit
with fluency builder.
What can I get you?
I'll have a Cosmo, please.
Dude, you can't order a Cosmo.
That's a ladies' drink.
You're embarrassing me.
What are you talking about?
It's a good drink.
It's too soft.
Order something with
a little more kick to it.
Fine.
I'll have a sex on the beach.
You have got to be kidding me.
Come on.
It's delicious.
Especially when served with
a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it.
I'm ordering for you.
I'll have a scotch on the rocks and
my friend here will have a Manhattan.
Put it on my tab.
Here.
Now this is a real drink.
Strong.
This is going to get me wasted.
That's the idea.
All right.
We're back.
So now let's talk a little bit more
about these drinks on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So Marco, there are
many different ways to
talk about drinks, but
the most important ones
that we often
discuss, especially with
cocktails, is weak drinks
versus strong drinks.
That's right.
Weak drinks versus strong drinks.
Now usually the cosmo
or maybe the sex on the
beach, it's considered
to be a weak drink.
That's right.
So it's not very strong
because there's less alcohol.
Like a cosmo has fruit
juice, like cranberry
juice, and the sex on
the beach is very fruity.
So it makes it less alcohol-y.
That's right.
And actually, those two
also have one type of alcohol.
So it's not very strong,
whereas maybe a
Manhattan has all this
mix of bourbon and other
drinks as well, so it will
be a strong alcoholic drink.
Yeah, and scotch on the rocks is
also very strong because it's just scotch.
Right.
You're not mixing it with anything.
No, there's just some ice and
some scotch, so that's a strong drink.
Okay.
So obviously, his friend was saying
that all those drinks are too weak.
You should order something
with a little more kick to it.
So in this context, kick means strength.
So alcohol, he wants a drink
that's not weak, that's strong.
So a strong drink has
more kick than a weak drink.
So can we use this with
food or with other situations?
You can, but with food,
it usually means spice.
So Indian food tends
to have a lot of kick to it.
That means it's very spicy.
Okay, so with alcohol,
it's strong with food,
it's usually spicy if
this rice has a kick to it.
It means it's a little spicy.
That's right.
So just think about kick as meaning that
something is strong or has a strong flavor.
Okay.
Very good.
Now, when they were
ordering, they didn't pay
immediately because
she said, "Put it on my tab.
" All right.
So to put something on a tab, this is really
important when you're going to a bar or
restaurant and you
want to order drinks, a
tab is a bill that you
don't pay immediately.
Right.
The bartender will
write down all the drinks
that you have and all their
prices and you pay when you leave.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So if you put something on your
tab, you'll pay it later or when you leave.
That's right.
So normally at a bar in America,
you say, "I want to start a tab.
" That means I want to
start a bill and you give
the bartender your credit card and he
will keep your credit card until you leave.
Oh, really.
So he keeps your credit
card until you leave.
Because obviously,
maybe you start a tab and
then you want to leave and you
don't want to pay and it's poor.
Or people get a little bit drunk
and they forget they have to pay.
So bartenders now
keep your credit card so
that even if you forget to
pay, they can charge you.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
Very interesting.
And now for our last
phrase, he was a little
bit concerned because
this drink is so strong.
He said, "This is going
to get me wasted.
" Okay.
So to be wasted or to get wasted
means to get very, very drunk.
To drink too much.
So if you say, "I'm wasted,"
it means I'm very drunk.
I'm very drunk.
You could say, "Oh, look
at those boys over there.
They're all wasted.
They're all, you know,
being drunk and sick.
" Yeah.
Okay.
So it's a very informal,
very casual kind of a
colloquial way of saying being
drunk or being intoxicated.
That's right.
So it's something we often use with friends
or as, you know, with young people, but
it's not something
you want to use in your
English class because
it's not a good thing to be.
Not a good thing to be wasted.
Okay.
Very good.
So now let's take a break
and listen to our dialogue one
last time and we'll be
back to talk a little bit more.
What can I get you?
I'll have a cosmic, please.
Dude, you can't order a cosmo.
That's a ladies' drink.
You're embarrassing me.
What are you talking about?
It's a good drink.
It's too soft.
Order something with
a little more kick to it.
Fine.
I'll have a sex on the beach.
You have got to be kidding me.
Come on.
It's delicious.
Especially when served with
a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it.
I'm ordering for you.
I'll have a scotch on the rocks and
my friend here will have a Manhattan.
Put it on my tab.
Here.
Now this is a real drink.
Strong.
This is going to get me wasted.
That's the idea.
All right.
So about cocktails, liquors.
What is your favorite
cocktail when you go out?
I almost always order gin and tonic.
That's my cocktail.
So gin is another type of liquor.
That's right.
Gin is another type of
liquor, like vodka or whiskey.
Has a very unique taste.
And tonic is a kind of water, but
it has a certain flavor to it, right?
It has a flavor to it.
So gin and tonic usually has some
gin, some tonic water, and some lime.
But the tonic water is
kind of bubbly, right?
That's right.
It's bubbly.
That's, I like bubbly drinks.
It's like champagne and stuff like that.
Yes.
Exactly.
I see.
What's your favorite?
I am a whiskey guy.
And so I usually order something like
this scotch on the rocks or something.
I never like to mix it with anything else.
And especially I really don't
like having sweet drinks.
Ah, so you're a purest.
Kind of.
It's just that, you know,
when the sweet alcohol
and things that are sweet, I don't
really think go that well together.
Now, I think, I think I
agree, although there
are some sweet
alcohols, our Italian friends
will be familiar with Limon cello, which is
that it's a dessert, the core, which tastes
like lemon or also kalua,
kalua, which is very sweet.
It's kind of like, it's a
coffee alcohol, right?
So many people like to put kalua
in their coffee to have Irish coffee.
That's right.
Actually, the alcoholic
world is, is very vast.
And actually, many people don't drink
alcohol, any people may have it occasionally.
So, but the other
interesting thing is that
usually countries have a
national alcoholic drink.
So for example, the Mexican national
alcoholic drink would be tequila.
That's right.
Or Russian, Eastern European, the vodka.
So in your country, maybe you have
a local or a national alcoholic drink.
We would be very interested to know about.
That's right.
Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there.
All right, guys.
See you.
Bye.